

HELEN KATALI

BABCP Accredited CBT Therapist, Perinatal specialist practitioner and practice background in psychiatric and community nursing.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: info@healthcity.org.uk, https://healthcity.org.uk

Professional summary

I am a Fully accredited and passionate CBT Therapist. 22 years of working with complex and severe mental health cases. I am warm, empathetic and compassionate with excellent ability to form therapeutic alliances. I have successfully treated large numbers of mental health cases. I have experience working with complex cases, co-morbidity and can manage risk efficiently. I am naturally enthusiastic, optimistic and very much enjoy my role as a therapist, therefore I achieve results fast, meet deadlines. Manage cases all while providing high quality care.

Professional Accreditation:

British Association of Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapists (BABCP) 05/11/2019 to date.

Skills

- CBT Therapist; great experience in working with OCD, maternal OCD, Anxiety, social phobias, PTSD, Perfectionism, psychosis, depression, Specialist in delivering treatment for clients suffering with Perinatal mental health difficulties.
- Great experience in utilising NLP, DBT, Mindfulness, Tapping and energy medicine.
- Leadership and Management
- Excellent Mental health Nursing
- Assessment of care needs
- Formulation
- Training
- Teaching
- Coaching, mentoring
- Supervising
- Appraising

Education

08/2001

Kingston University|Surrey Bachelor of Science Mental Health Nursing

08/2014

South Bank University London

Post Graduate Degree in Cognitive Behavioural therapy

08/1996

Greenwich University|London, ENG

Bachelor of Arts: Business Management -Marketing

Work History

2014 to present

South London & Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust | London, ENG

CBT Therapist/Perinatal specialist practitioner Team lead.

I work with moderate to severe mental health disorders, from common to complex anxiety, psychosis, varied OCD subtypes, Maternal OCD, Birth Traumas, Mother and baby relationships PTSD, Childhood trauma, Bipolar, Personality Disorder

I have managed many suicidal and self-harm cases and can manage risk effectively.

I am registered with BABCP and work within professional guidelines.

I am experienced in providing online CBT, flexible in adapting to different methods of providing therapy

I am competent in writing reports; to the GP, to social services, to court if needed with the client's consent

11/2009 - 2014

South London and Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust | London, ENG

Perinatal specialist mental health worker

Assess, plan and manage care of women with severe and enduring mental health difficulties in the antenatal and postal period up to a year.

Coordinate care and liaise with the Multi agency in risk management and planning.

Offer training to the multi-agency, write reports for social care, court, and update the GP.

Deliver CBT therapy to clients

02/2007 - 11/2011

South London and Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust | London, ENG

Community Psychiatric Nurse

Assessing, planning, managing and coordinating care of the adults with long-term enduring mental health difficulties.

04/2002 - 02/2007

South London and Maudsley NHS Trust | London, ENG

Senior Clinical Charge Nurse

Acute inpatient ward

Day to day of running a busy acute mental health ward. Dealing with emergencies on a daily basis. Responding to emergencies on the whole site as a duty senior nurse. Ensuring safe clinical delivery in an emergency. Managing 136 suit. Ensuring safe admission and discharge. Liaising with the community mental health teams, service managers and other multi agencies. Running client groups, training and supervising staff. Ensuring daily safe staffing levels within the financial restraints

Personality

I am a mature person with good humour, good attitude, responsible, diplomatic, approachable, hardworking, physically and mentally fit, flexible, cooperative, assertive, trustworthy and enthusiastic. I love and I am passionate about serving humanity and utilising the limited resources to the full capacity